# **Tony Healy**

CIO IT Transformation & Business Change Leader

tonyhealy1@live.com

# Summary

I am commercially oriented, pragmatic and accomplished senior technology leader, with over 20 years' experience in delivering effective IT Strategies, Business Transformation Programmes and innovation. I specialise in "commercialising" technology through translation of business needs into clear, executable plans based on a strong technology insight in how to optimise business processes and drive operational efficiencies. I have worked in a variety of multi-national and global industries (Plc, Ltd & Family) that include telecommunications, logistics, transportation, retail, technology, education and healthcare.

## Specialities:

- Budget management
- Change management
- Vendor management
- Strategy
- Security
- Executive leadership
- Relationship management
- M&A
- Out-sourcing
- Cloud
- In-sourcing
- Enterprise architecture
- Digital transformation
- Project management
- System automation
- Process optimisation
- Board experience
- Workflow management

# Experience

# ICT Director at Wall Family Europe Ltd

January 2016 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Wall Family Enterprise is a family and privately-owned, global portfolio of businesses with a strong market leadership position in the library and learning industries. Office are located in the US and UK, and they

employ c800 employees. As a member of the European executive leadership team, I am responsible for defining, communicating and implementing technology that can better enable the business to grow and achieve its goals. I have done this by creating and implementing an ICT strategy for 5 B2B and B2C companies (Maudesport, Technology Supplies, Demco, Timstar & Collexi) that compliment the business goals and global strategy.

## Company Director at T Healy Consulting Ltd

September 2015 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Specialising in ICT consultancy around transformation, strategy, change, structure, security and infrastructure.

## Interim Head of Retail IT Service and Operations at The Co-op

October 2015 - December 2015 (3 months)

Co-Op is the UK's fifth biggest food retailer with c2,800 stores and c62,000 employees. I was responsible for designing a service and support structure and strategy to meet the needs of the group by utilizing an in-house team of 106 and off shore support from TATA across the retail estate with full end to end support including WMS, logistics, support, tills and comms.

# **Group I.T Director at Synexus**

March 2012 - October 2015 (3 years 8 months)

Synexus is the world's leading global Site Management Organisation (SMO), with a network of 28 dedicated research 68 affiliate sites and 1000 employees. I was responsible for the management and co-ordination of all aspects of global IT applications, infrastructure, BI, projects and strategy in the UK, Germany, Poland, Bulgaria and South Africa. I Led all IT initiatives around acquisitions of new companies and transfer to a new Private Equity partner.

# Global Head of Group Infrastructure, Communications & Security at Promethean

August 2010 - March 2012 (1 year 8 months)

Promethean is a global education company that improves the quality of education by developing, integrating and implementing innovative 21st century learning environments. I had overall accountability for all IT services across 16 sites in the UK, Atlanta, Seattle, Hong Kong, China, Australia, Dubai, Germany and France. Responsible for ensuring that all sites were available 24/7 and the core data centre and network was secure, resilient and met all data protection legislation across all countries.

### Group Head of Technology & Service at Punch Taverns

November 2006 - August 2010 (3 years 10 months)

Punch is one of the UK's largest leased pub companies, with a portfolio of more than 3,500 pubs nationwide and 10000 employees. I had overall responsibility for ensuring that four regional head offices (including Sprit group), two data-centres and all managed pubs were secure and able to operate under any conditions. Responsibility for ensuring that all IT service related application and system issues were dealt with and

managed in agreement with the applicable SLA. Responsibility for a team of 103 covering service delivery, network, application support, infrastructure, PMO and BI.

## Head of I.T - EMEA at FWL Technologies

September 2003 - November 2006 (3 years 3 months)

FWL Technologies supplies global operational software solutions to the freight industry, shipping industry and large logistics providers. Its comprehensive integrated operational software solutions spans the entire supply chain. An independent company, FWL has offices in Europe, America, SE Asia and India.

#### Technical Systems Manager at Stagecoach Bus

June 1999 - September 2003 (4 years 4 months)

Stagecoach UK Bus is part of the Stagecoach Group and is one of the largest bus operators in the UK. They operate express and local bus services across the country, as well as a network of intercity operations under the megabus.com brand with 30000 employees.

## 3rd Line Technical Support Team Leader at BT

July 1994 - June 1999 (5 years)

Support and Deal with all technical escalation for BT Internet

# Certifications

**MCSE** 

Microsoft

**CCNA** 

Cisco

Prince 2

**CISSP** 

**ITIL** 

QA Ltd

**CCA** 

Citrix

**OCP** 

Oracle

#### **Creating Your IT Strategy**

LinkedIn November 2016

## **Introduction to Ethical Hacking**

LinkedIn November 2016

**Influencing Others** 

LinkedIn November 2016

# **Projects**

# IBM FlexSystem with v7000 storage, vSphere 5, Backup,

July 2012 to October 2012

Members: Tony Healy, Anthony Houghton, Danial Taylor

Implement new IBM flex system infrastructure, backup processes, and migrate existing virtual and physical infrastructure to new platform.

- IBM PureFlex Chassis with 4 x240 Compute Nodes, 2 10Gb Chassis Switches
- 1 x IBM V7000 fully populated at Head Office
- 1 x IBM V7000 fully populated at DR Site
- FCoIP using 2 IBM SAN06 IP Routers for replication over IP
- 10Gb iSCSI connections for LAN/SAN Traffic
- All Compute nodes are running vSphere 5 Enterprise and all configured.
- Uplink trunks configured for LAN
- Array-Based replication using IBM Global Mirror with Change Volumes

## IBM FlexSystem with v7000 storage, vSphere 5, Backup,

July 2012 to October 2012

Members: Tony Healy, Danial Taylor, Anthony Houghton

Implement new IBM flex system infrastructure, backup processes, and migrate existing virtual and physical infrastructure to new platform.

- IBM PureFlex Chassis with 4 x240 Compute Nodes, 2 10Gb Chassis Switches
- 1 x IBM V7000 fully populated at Head Office
- 1 x IBM V7000 fully populated at DR Site
- FCoIP using 2 IBM SAN06 IP Routers for replication over IP
- 10Gb iSCSI connections for LAN/SAN Traffic
- All Compute nodes are running vSphere 5 Enterprise and all configured.
- Uplink trunks configured for LAN
- Array-Based replication using IBM Global Mirror with Change Volumes

#### **EMEA Integration Strategy**

May 2013 to October 2013

Members: Tony Healy, Danial Taylor, Anthony Houghton

Produce a strategy and design on how to integrate the EMEA offices into the group, Each office is independent and needs full integration. Design includes the following

Active Directory design eMail

Networking

Centralised Controls

Wide Area File Services

Desktop Support

Document will be submitted to the IT Director for Budget approval

# Cisco Meraki MDM/Wireless Implemenation

September 2013 to Present

Members: Tony Healy, Danial Taylor, Anthony Houghton

Implement MDM and Wireless

# Organizations

# **Corporate I.T Forum**

**Education & Skills Commission** 

March 2012 to Present

# Skills & Expertise

**IT Management** 

**Telephony** 

**Financial Control** 

**Security** 

**Telecommunications** 

**Contract Negotiation** 

**Problem Solving** 

**IT Service Management** 

**Disaster Recovery** 

**Outsourcing** 

**IT Strategy** 

ITIL

**ERP** 

**Business Continuity** 

**IT Governance** 

**Business Intelligence** 

Virtualization

**Stakeholder Management** 

**Program Management** 

**Change Management** 

**Integration** 

**Cloud Computing** 

**Business Process Improvement** 

**Business Analysis** 

**Data Center** 

**Enterprise Architecture** 

**IT Operations** 

**Business Transformation** 

Consultancy

**SLA** 

**Project Portfolio Management** 

**Team Leadership** 

**VMware** 

**Process Engineering** 

**Business Strategy** 

**Team Management** 

**Vendor Management** 

**PMO** 

**SharePoint** 

**Business Management** 

**People Management** 

E-commerce

**Solution Design** 

**Project Delivery** 

Governance

**Requirements Analysis** 

**Team Building** 

**Service Delivery** 

Management

**Information Technology** 

# Education

# South trafford college

A levels, Maths, science, computer studies, 1994 - 1996

Grade: 2 x B 1 x C

# Jeff joseph sale moor college of technology

Gcse, Maths, english, science, history, geography, 1989 - 1994

Grade: 8 b's

# **Interests**

**CIO Consultancy** 

Strategic Planning

**Operational Development** 

# Languages

# **English**

# **Tony Healy**

CIO IT Transformation & Business Change Leader

tonyhealy1@live.com



# 17 people have recommended Tony

"Tony is an extremely well rounded IT Director having significant experience across strategy, infrastructure, applications, service delivery, SLA management, and managing the user experience. He has worked with both internal teams and outsource partners. Within WFEL a key deliverable has been a root and branch reviews of global business systems, identifying strengths, gaps and setting a 3 year road map with milestones for achievement. I have no hesitation in recommending Tony."

— **Dawn West**, *HR Director*, *Wall Family Europe Ltd*, worked directly with Tony at Wall Family Europe Ltd

"Having worked with Tony on a significant IT project I have found him a pleasure to work with, he is incredibly knowledgeable and has gone out his way to ensure the project is setup for success. Tony was a key part of the selection, planning and implementation process. I would have no reservation in recommending Tony."

— **Sean Harrison-Smith**, *Owner*, *Ceterna Ltd*, was a consultant or contractor to Tony at Wall Family Europe Ltd

"I have had the pleasure of working with Tony at Wall Family Europe. We worked through a period of significant transition in the business and Tony's cool head and strategic mind was invaluable. Tony has a rare blend of skills in terms of high level technical and strategic ability coupled with very good communication and people skills. Tony would be an asset for any organisation."

— **Darren Liffen**, *UK Director of Operations*, *Wall Family Europe*, worked directly with Tony at Wall Family Europe Ltd

"I had the pleasure of working alongside Tony whilst I was leading on the introduction of a Global HRIS at Synexus. Tony was always approachable, offered welcomed and practical advice and supported me (on many occasions) with technical difficulties and international challenges."

— Emma R., HR Project Manager, Synexus Clinical Research Ltd, worked indirectly for Tony at Synexus

"Tony lead the implementation of a new system in a fast moving organisation. He showed extreme resilience, professionalism and a "can do" attitude at all times to get the job done. A very well respected IT director

and an absolute pleasure to work with. He would be an asset to any business undergoing significant change, through his leadership, direction and team working skills."

#### — **Shrutisha Morris**, worked directly with Tony at Synexus

"I have had the pleasure of working with Tony Healy over the past few years within my current role. He is a consummate professional and his knowledge and drive enable him to achieve results. Having worked on multiple Global projects and roll-outs together, Tony has consistently enabled successful outcomes. I would recommend Tony to any organization that is looking for top notch individuals."

# — **Jon Paul Giorgi**, was a consultant or contractor to Tony at Promethean

"It's been a pleasure working with Tony at Promethean around the businesses Data Centre Strategy and Infrastructure 3.0. I've always found him to the point, with a clear vision on what the business has wanted to achieve with a strong drive and the ability to deliver."

# — Ed Knowles, was a consultant or contractor to Tony at Promethean

"Working with Tony is fantastic, he is always level-headed, approachable and knowledgeable. He gets involved to resolve a situation so that the right paths can be decided. Tony always looks after his team members."

## — **Danial Taylor**, worked indirectly for Tony at Promethean

"Tony is without doubt the most consistent level headed manager i have ever worked for. He strives to get the best from his team without the use of an iron rod and is always willing to get his hands dirty if the need arises. In short a fantastic all rounder!! I would have no hesitation in recommending him to any company."

## — Steve Rothwell, reported to Tony at Promethean

"I have worked with Tony at Promethean from day 1 and was invited in to rationalise costs and advise where savings could be made. Working closely together on several projects we realised savings of over £250,000.00 within Mobility and Landline areas, whilst streamlining billing and reporting procedures resulting in a reduction of over 10 man hours per week. I would highly recommend Tony as a consummate professional who simply gets the job done. He would certainly be an asset to any organisation looking to improve business efficiencies and move forward during these increasingly difficult times. Stuart Sharrock"

#### — **Stuart Sharrock**, was a consultant or contractor to Tony at Promethean

"Tony started at Promethean about a week after me, and in his 18 months has made some very positive steps in re-organising Promethean's IT structure. As a manager i find him to be very approachable, honest, and

hardworking. Very technically minded, he has helped make me a much better IT technician and i'd have no hesitation in recommending him to any organisation."

## — **Ian Burnett**, worked indirectly for Tony at Promethean

"I have worked for Tony for almost 18 months and have really benefited from his support and guidance. When he started with the company, he immediately made a huge impact on the business, especially within the IT team. He is a very supportive manager and really knows what he is talking about. He always makes time to help you out if you are struggling with anything, whether it be technically or politically challenging. Tony is particularly good at seeing past all the rubbish and getting straight to the issue at hand, and coming up with a workable solution. I hope to have the pleasure of working with Tony for some time to come, or again in the future, and have no problem recommending him to any company."

# — Martin Pearson, worked indirectly for Tony at Promethean

"Tony and I took over ownership of a very challenging and complex transformation programme. He demonstrated incredible skill and experience to successfully deliver where others had failed. He handled issues in a clam and pragmatic manner that kept the programme on track ensuring successful delivery leading to realisation of benefits. An excellent leader!"

#### — Ramesh Patel, was a consultant or contractor to Tony at Punch Taverns

"Tony quickly earned by admiration and respect as an outstanding leader and manager during the regrettably brief period I reported into him. I have worked in a number of roles in my career and never have I come across someone with such an ability to cut through the irrelevant and get straight to the heart of an issue. In an extremely short period of Time Tony started making a huge impact and his presence was felt throughout the company. His ability to drive change and make improvements was astonishing. What is more, Tony has an excellent interpersonal style and his management skills lifted the morale of everyone in his reporting line. Tony is extremely hard-working, conscientious, and very hands-on and focussed. The expectation placed on his shoulders was little short of incredible and yet somehow he managed to deliver with little resource and even less time, due in no small part to his tireless work rate and no doubt an extremely understanding wife! I cannot recommend Tony strongly enough. I sincerely hope to work with him again at some point."

#### — **Andrew Hawthorne**, reported to Tony at Punch Taverns

"Tony is an excellent manager with an uncanny ability to build teams and motivate his staff. His technical knowledge is extensive and he was a consistently strong leader in any given situation. I have no hesitation in recommending Tony and would have no hesitation in working for him again."

## — Sarah Prowell, reported to Tony at Punch Taverns

"I first worked with Tony in 2000 during a brief initial contract with Stagecoach. When I went back for a longer engagement in 2002, Tony was still there, and working as a field service engineer. In that role, Tony had a good attitude, working the long hours necessary to satisfy customers and rectify issues in a patch stretching from Carlisle to Manchester to Chesterfield - so much so that he built and maintained relationships with senior management from the operating comapnies, so much so that he often had a crisis of conscience trying to work out which 'Christmas Do's ' to attend! Tony consistently closed more helpdesk calls than the other engineers and was a self-starter. I was responsible for moving him to the headquarters as soon as an opening was available, where he maintained his high standards, supporting PCs and then onto server support. Tony consistently expected more of himself and obtained his CCNA during 2003 - he also took on responsibility for the Mitel phone switch and after brief training, became knowledgeable about that too. He was a hard working, valuable and loyal member of the team - someone that could be relied upon to give 110% on a regular basis."

## — Joseph Rose, managed Tony at Stagecoach Bus

"Tony is an exceptionally talented IT systems technician. Able to size up the needs of the customer and draw parallels to the needs of the business, he doesn't rest until his customers are satisified. Drawing on a wide range of experience and environments, he is able to deliver on deadlines and within targets, dealing with minor issues and not missing the bigger picture."

— Philip Rigby, worked directly with Tony at Stagecoach Bus

Contact Tony on LinkedIn